<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title> on Speex </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://johnspickes.github.io/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>John Spickes</author>
    <copyright>John Spickes</copyright>
    <updated>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 14:36:47 EST</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s all this, then?</title>
      <link>https://johnspickes.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 14:36:47 EST</pubDate>
      <author>John Spickes</author>
      <guid>https://johnspickes.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>This is the personal blog of John Spickes. It is generated using Hugo. Here you may find writing on various topics, perhaps including: Rationality Nonviolent Communication Politics Philosophy Parenting Et Cetera I love getting feedback. Please feel free to send me email at john@spickes.net.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Approach</title>
      <link>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/new-blog-new-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 12:23:54 EST</pubDate>
      <author>John Spickes</author>
      <guid>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/new-blog-new-approach/</guid>
      <description>I want to try a different approach to my online interactions. I&amp;rsquo;ve played with Facebook for a while, and I&amp;rsquo;ve decided, for now anyway, that it&amp;rsquo;s not my thing. Other social media seem to have similar problems. Fighting Conversations on Facebook are too often heated. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s that everything is open - all conversations potentially have an audience. Maybe that drives people to feel that they must &amp;ldquo;win&amp;rdquo; every argument. Often, the conversation participants are &amp;ldquo;friends of friends&amp;rdquo;, writing to people they don&amp;rsquo;t know, making assumptions about them based on little or no information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying Hugo</title>
      <link>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/trying-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 08:23:54 EST</pubDate>
      <author>John Spickes</author>
      <guid>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/trying-hugo/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m giving Hugo a try. Why? I want my files. I like them to be here, on my machine, editable offline, going with me wherever I go. I like Markdown. I like my files to be in a format I can easily read and edit. I like being able to easily move my content elsewhere when I change my mind. And I will. Markdown is easy to read and convert. I like using my own editor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End of Stoic Week 2014</title>
      <link>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/end-of-stoic-week-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 17:55:35 EST</pubDate>
      <author>John Spickes</author>
      <guid>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/end-of-stoic-week-2014/</guid>
      <description>What follows is a journal entry I wrote on December 1, 2014. I kind of half-assed my way through Stoic week, and certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t give it the effort it deserved. My excuse is that I was trying to be a good parent, and neglected the Stoic Week practice for that. Anyway, I do feel I came away with some useful nuggets. One of Stoicism&amp;rsquo;s main ideas is to be conscious of what&amp;rsquo;s under your control and what isn&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Scared of Net Neutrality</title>
      <link>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/im-scared-of-net-neutrality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
      <author>John Spickes</author>
      <guid>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/im-scared-of-net-neutrality/</guid>
      <description>My unpopular opinion of the day: I&amp;rsquo;m scared of Net Neutrality. I have no doubt that this seems positively outlandish to many people, so let me explain. Of course I&amp;rsquo;m for good internet service, and all that. I don&amp;rsquo;t want my ISP direct my traffic to services they&amp;rsquo;d prefer I visit, or restrict what I can do, or any of that. I&amp;rsquo;m totally for freedom on the internet. So, you may ask, what am I worried about?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papa&#39;s Tool Box</title>
      <link>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/papas-tool-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>John Spickes</author>
      <guid>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/papas-tool-box/</guid>
      <description>Over the weekend I was working in the garage, and I came across an old tool box that I inherited from my grandfather. We called him Papa. I remember him often working on some engine or other, for his boat, or his lawn mower, or his truck. His hands were often a little greasy as I remember him. I set about sorting through the contents of this old, rusted tool box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moral Judgement as an Impediment to Happiness</title>
      <link>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/moral-judgement-impediment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
      <author>John Spickes</author>
      <guid>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/moral-judgement-impediment/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning about something called Nonviolent Communication. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to go into the whole topic of NVC here - I just want to write down some thoughts I&amp;rsquo;ve been rolling over in my mind regarding certain ideas that I encountered when learning about it. This hasn&amp;rsquo;t really been built into a well-formed essay yet, so forgive my inelegance. In particular, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about the extent to which we apply moral judgement, and the effects that has on our happiness, relationships, and communication, and in particular how this relates to parenting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Same Old Philosophy, New Reasons</title>
      <link>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/same-old-philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>John Spickes</author>
      <guid>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/same-old-philosophy/</guid>
      <description>So, yeah&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time since I last used this blog - but you don&amp;rsquo;t want to read a blog post about how I haven&amp;rsquo;t been using my blog. I&amp;rsquo;ll cut to the meat, and come back to the blog-related stuff at the end. I have spent far too many brain cycles thinking about politics. I&amp;rsquo;ve come to realize this over the course of the last few years. For many years before that, I spent a great amount of mental and emotional energy on political issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://johnspickes.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>John Spickes</author>
      <guid>https://johnspickes.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;d like to talk with me about something I&amp;rsquo;ve written here, please do one of the following: Call me Talk to me in person Send me an email to john@spickes.net</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

