<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Nvc on Speex </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://johnspickes.github.io/tags/nvc/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>John Spickes</author>
    <copyright>John Spickes</copyright>
    <updated>Mon, 07 May 2018 17:47:00 -0500</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linguistic Misattribution</title>
      <link>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/linguistic-misattribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 17:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>John Spickes</author>
      <guid>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/linguistic-misattribution/</guid>
      <description>One of the skills that I have been practicing in my study of NVC, mindfulness, and rationality is what is variously called &amp;ldquo;original seeing&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;seeing with fresh eyes&amp;rdquo;. It is the skill of observing a thing simply, as though for the first time, with the intention of seeing the thing as it really is. This involves shutting down one&amp;rsquo;s automatic thought processes, and avoiding the application of judgments that come to us naturally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family HEART Camp 2016</title>
      <link>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/heart-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 13:04:06 EDT</pubDate>
      <author>John Spickes</author>
      <guid>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/heart-camp/</guid>
      <description>I want to share an experience that my family had for the first time in June 2016, and which I think will become a fixture in our lives for the foreseeable future. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about an event called Family HEART Camp.
It is rather difficult to describe this experience briefly. It&amp;rsquo;s also hard to describe without sounding &amp;hellip; well &amp;hellip; maybe a bit crazy. People often exaggerate and use superlatives inappropriately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cause of Emotion</title>
      <link>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/cause-of-emotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 15:58:43 EDT</pubDate>
      <author>John Spickes</author>
      <guid>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/cause-of-emotion/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;He made me angry.&amp;rdquo; This is a common way of talking in modern western society. We talk as though our emotions are directly caused by external stimuli.
It&amp;rsquo;s simple stimulus and response. In this example, some action &amp;ldquo;he&amp;rdquo; has taken has caused my anger; and in real life it often feels like this is what happens. The cause (his action) occurs very shortly before the effect (my anger), and if he hadn&amp;rsquo;t taken his action, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be angry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moral Judgement as an Impediment to Happiness</title>
      <link>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/moral-judgement-impediment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
      <author>John Spickes</author>
      <guid>https://johnspickes.github.io/post/moral-judgement-impediment/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning about something called Nonviolent Communication. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to go into the whole topic of NVC here - I just want to write down some thoughts I&amp;rsquo;ve been rolling over in my mind regarding certain ideas that I encountered when learning about it. This hasn&amp;rsquo;t really been built into a well-formed essay yet, so forgive my inelegance.
In particular, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about the extent to which we apply moral judgement, and the effects that has on our happiness, relationships, and communication, and in particular how this relates to parenting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

